{
  "quizzes": {
    "_id": { "$oid": "616ac07f87a221a8a4935bc8" },
    "quizname": "Light1",
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Describe an activity to show that the incident ray, the reflected ray and\n(d) Night birds have  ____________ cones than rods in their  _______ .",
        "distractors": [
          { "distractor": "eyes", "meaning": "look at" },
          {
            "distractor": "timeserver",
            "meaning": "one who conforms to current ways and opinions for personal advantage"
          },
          { "distractor": "sing from same hymnbook", "meaning": null },
          { "distractor": "agreeance", "meaning": null }
        ],
        "correct_answer": "eyes"
      },
      {
        "question": "The light ray, which strikes any surface,\nlight which is made up of several\nthe plane  _______ , the incident ray and\nthe reflected ray on the paper with the\n _______  at the point where the incident\nray strikes the  _______ .",
        "distractors": [
          { "distractor": "mirror", "meaning": "reflect as if in a mirror" },
          {
            "distractor": "reflector",
            "meaning": "optical telescope consisting of a large concave mirror that produces an image that is magnified by the eyepiece"
          },
          { "distractor": "way of cross", "meaning": null },
          { "distractor": "beauty dish", "meaning": null }
        ],
        "correct_answer": "mirror"
      },
      {
        "question": "The light  _______ , which strikes any surface,\nlight which is made up of several\nthe plane mirror, the incident  _______  and\nthe reflected  _______  on the paper with the\nmirror at the point where the incident\n _______  strikes the mirror.",
        "distractors": [
          { "distractor": "ray", "meaning": "emit as rays" },
          {
            "distractor": "back",
            "meaning": "shift to a counterclockwise direction"
          },
          { "distractor": "spinate", "meaning": null },
          { "distractor": "t spine", "meaning": null }
        ],
        "correct_answer": "ray"
      },
      {
        "question": "Ü Regular  _______  takes place when light is\n(ii) Incident ray, reflected ray and the normal\nÜ Image formed in a plane mirror undergoes\nÜ Parts of the eye are cornea, iris, pupil, lens,\n5.",
        "distractors": [
          {
            "distractor": "reflection",
            "meaning": "the ability to reflect beams or rays"
          },
          { "distractor": "heat", "meaning": "gain heat or get hot" },
          {
            "distractor": "time",
            "meaning": "assign a time for an activity or event"
          },
          { "distractor": "physical quantity", "meaning": null }
        ],
        "correct_answer": "reflection"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the  _______  of incidence of a ray if the reflected ray is at an  _______  of\nA ray of light is incident on one at an\nDraw the reflected ray from the second\nmirror.",
        "distractors": [
          { "distractor": "angle", "meaning": "move or proceed at an angle" },
          { "distractor": "white man", "meaning": null },
          { "distractor": "dorhawk", "meaning": null },
          { "distractor": "felwort", "meaning": null }
        ],
        "correct_answer": "angle"
      },
      {
        "question": "The light ray, which strikes any surface,\nlight which is made up of several\nthe plane mirror, the  _______  ray and\nthe reflected ray on the paper with the\nmirror at the point where the  _______ \nray strikes the mirror.",
        "distractors": [
          {
            "distractor": "incident",
            "meaning": "falling or striking of light rays on something"
          },
          {
            "distractor": "event",
            "meaning": "a phenomenon located at a single point in space-time; the fundamental observational entity in relativity theory"
          },
          {
            "distractor": "cyclic",
            "meaning": "forming a whorl or having parts arranged in a whorl"
          },
          { "distractor": "accidental", "meaning": null }
        ],
        "correct_answer": "incident"
      },
      {
        "question": "Ü Regular reflection takes place when light is\n(ii) Incident ray, reflected ray and the normal\nÜ  _______  formed in a plane mirror undergoes\nÜ Parts of the eye are cornea, iris, pupil, lens,\n5.",
        "distractors": [
          {
            "distractor": "image",
            "meaning": "imagine; conceive of; see in one's mind"
          },
          {
            "distractor": "representation",
            "meaning": "an activity that stands as an equivalent of something or results in an equivalent"
          },
          { "distractor": "representationalism", "meaning": null },
          {
            "distractor": "depiction",
            "meaning": "a drawing of the outlines of forms or objects"
          }
        ],
        "correct_answer": "image"
      },
      {
        "question": "Describe an  _______  to show that the incident ray, the reflected ray and\n(d) Night birds have  ____________ cones than rods in their eyes.",
        "distractors": [
          {
            "distractor": "activity",
            "meaning": "a process existing in or produced by nature (rather than by the intent of human beings"
          },
          {
            "distractor": "trick",
            "meaning": "an attempt to get you to do something foolish or imprudent"
          },
          { "distractor": "have someone's number", "meaning": null },
          {
            "distractor": "scene",
            "meaning": "a situation treated as an observable object"
          }
        ],
        "correct_answer": "activity"
      },
      {
        "question": "allow more light in the eye, when\nBehind the pupil of the eye is a lens\n _______  has green eyes, we refer actually\neye.",
        "distractors": [
          {
            "distractor": "person",
            "meaning": "a human body (usually including the clothing"
          },
          { "distractor": "biometeorology", "meaning": null },
          { "distractor": "bioluminescence", "meaning": null },
          { "distractor": "probiosis", "meaning": null }
        ],
        "correct_answer": "person"
      },
      {
        "question": "The light ray, which strikes any surface,\nlight which is made up of several\nthe plane mirror, the incident ray and\nthe reflected ray on the  _______  with the\nmirror at the point where the incident\nray strikes the mirror.",
        "distractors": [
          { "distractor": "paper", "meaning": "cover with paper" },
          {
            "distractor": "wood",
            "meaning": "a golf club with a long shaft used to hit long shots; originally made with a wooden head"
          },
          {
            "distractor": "column",
            "meaning": "a line of units following one after another"
          },
          {
            "distractor": "wax",
            "meaning": "any of various substances of either mineral origin or plant or animal origin; they are solid at normal temperatures and insoluble in water"
          }
        ],
        "correct_answer": "paper"
      },
      {
        "question": "The light ray, which strikes any  _______ ,\nlight which is made up of several\nthe plane mirror, the incident ray and\nthe reflected ray on the paper with the\nmirror at the point where the incident\nray strikes the mirror.",
        "distractors": [
          { "distractor": "surface", "meaning": "on the surface" },
          { "distractor": "interleaf", "meaning": null },
          { "distractor": "bifront", "meaning": null },
          {
            "distractor": "chicken",
            "meaning": "a foolhardy competition; a dangerous activity that is continued until one competitor becomes afraid and stops"
          }
        ],
        "correct_answer": "surface"
      }
    ]
  }
}
